Now let's try that again good afternoon everyone.
Perfect.
All right we're going to go back in time will quick we're going to go back in time to august first two
thousand and twelve.
We've all gathered together for the opening of the new
york stock exchange we work for company called night capital group so
...the developers are the operations team
were so excited about our new software...having a party to celebrate it going life
it trades in the new york stock exchange were so excited that we wrote this application
that is going to show...in real-time exactly how much money we're going to start making
...we've invited all of rc level executives are product owner our stakeholders
...all really, really
excited so let's just sit here and watch exactly how much money we're going to start making.
And, let that sink in for second because every second
we're losing one hundred and seventy thousand dollars.
One hundred and seventy thousand-dollars is being lost every second our software
is running clearly this is not what we expected so the developers and
the operations guys come together and start trying to figure out what in the world happen how
are we losing one hundred and seventy thousand dollars per second we deployed our software to eight
...of which we find out one of them is doing the wrong thing so clearly we
try and fix it after done fixing it we now have eight
...doing the wrong thing so we're losing even more money this is because we had
...deployment manually we had to do...deployment by hand we had no way
to rolling this stuff back in case of emergency.
After running for just one-minute just
sixty seconds we're going to lose over ten million dollars.
Like geniuses we keep trying to fix
this for forty five minutes so at ten fifteen
someone basically just shuts the system down go into the server room to start taken over
...pulling wires out of the wall do whatever you have to but stop the
software from trading after forty five minutes when the dust settled
they had lost four hundred and sixty million dollars.
So, the software that I'm going to talk to-you today about to say
this company half-a-billion dollars the saddest thing about this entire story
...make a word of it up this actually happened this is a real
story because they did not have a property...pipeline they didn't have the software and
place necessary to prevent this from happening so this was not capital group but my question to
you is what is the impact to your organization are you the poor guy has to have the pager when
you do a deployment you the guy that gets the call...in the database changes
didn't go incorrectly right I've been that guy it takes years
...your life every time you do a deployment this poor guy he not
only ruined his life...is entire companies like they literally went bankrupt you can go and look up
...group sec filing is basically a
twenty-eight page bug reports about how this actually happened.
Now that I have your attention my name is donovan brown and I'm going
...the next hour with you talking to you about
deb ops in specifically the offering that we have you might have seen some of this
an edge talk the only difference...minor but actually bits...going to go a little bit
deeper and talk about how we can actually implement this stuff.
Before joining microsoft I was what they call...process consultant very similar to
add that's a fancy way of saying I...all over the world installing and implementing
team foundation server to fs for those you don't know is a collaboration hub
that source control work item tracking build all these great things...you need to
taken idea in turning into a working piece of software
...you covered as you covered now when I started seven years ago
wasn't always the case I show up at a client site will be implementing team foundation server and
...source control in there I get...bug tracking in
their the work item tracking in there even get automated build...there...all exciting the look
...like what's next and...ok donovan we have this build how we now get it to
development environment and then from the development environment into qa and
...into production...we're doing that we
...make sure we monitor the web dot concedes and change that stuff and I politely
just start packing up my stuff backing away from the table hoping they didn't notice I'm...to get out of there because
it was like audio guys I can't help you do that to fs has no facilities or didn't have
any facilities that allowed us to do that right they'd ask me nicely they give me those puppy the
guys I feel bad okay this is what if you what I would use I will take build?
And,...write you a custom task or I will write your custom activity what they will do
that will copy in x copy your files from build
...your dev environment that's as far as I can take you guys no matter how much you begging plead I can't get
build to wake
...and then promoted to qa and then wake back up again when you're ready for to promote
to production it just doesn't do that build should do build.
We needed something else that just simply did not exist back then that would take the code and actually release
it for us I joined microsoft december thirteenth.
Nineteen twenty thirteen just over a little bit over a year-ago about the same time we acquired the software
...be talking to you about today so we kind of
join together and I attach myself to it because I kept thinking
to myself wow if we had this piece of software when I was a process consultant
...been able to help my customers completely to actually give them everything that they were
wanting for and now we can give it to them right now so...attach myself to the hip to release
management I've been speaking about all over the world and I'm really excited to show you a deep level
...what we have new because...to all the pain points were kind of
...more stories over here before the talk we've addressed a lot of that stuff right and we've heard that
and I'm preaching that I'm speaking you today as a dsp that basically means
I sell the tools that I'm showing you today I've been recruited by
redmond come up to the mother ship so...I'm actually changing roles I'm going to
the engineering team and I'm going to take all those war stories with me and I'm going to help shape what we
produced coming forward to make sure that we have the best of
absolution that we possibly can we know that not everyone's on microsoft we know there's people out
there writing on linux we...people writing java we're going to help those people as well so nothing about that
...talk about some fun stuff you might have notice I didn't hear any laughing which I'm very shocked at the
twelve-plus occupy in the world and no one left of course we find...table I will be only one laughing.
I also competitive driver and I...a...developer
...I am you iceland code every single-day it's just what I
do to have fun I just happens to be what I do for a living as well.
I tweet...and I'll you can also...donovan...dot com my body
...snowboard just tweety that he...ten thousand followers
...some quick math if everyone in this room follows me rb catching up to
him and only need about nine thousand more.
So, help me make progress
...follow me on twitter and...can see if I get nine thousand more people to do that before the
into the week all right so let's go ahead and start talking about what we're really
...talk about it's about release management but this is a different talk
because I'm specifically talking about giving java code over into a linux
environment using the microsoft stack it's a world that is very.
For information or soft right what why would you ever expected java developer to be using
...deploy to a linux machine you just wouldn't have done in years past but we can actually do that
today we have great integration with companies like chef those are great guys they have spent countless
hours with me teaching the chef way of doing things to make sure that when
we integrate chef with rm were not bastard rising the way you're supposed to you chef
...using shift the proper way over layering on top of it the value
add that is release management so we've been working close with those guys great group of guys I can't say enough about
If you're familiar with chef you might not be ask...desired
...configurations I'm going to bring up to speed on what
dsp is what it can be used forked it's very similar almost put them in the same buckets right
...they solve very similar problems but we have
an offering for their to enough to works and linux we'll talk about that I want to dispel the fact that
...fs is just for dot net a lot of people...the impression that you guys
...fs you must be dot net developers as a process consultant I would go into a client and
I'd help them implement fs and then I realized they had a our builder t...java
team but they wouldn't let me talk to them and I didn't understand why because the tools that we have for
...work for java to they work for our builder so why won't you let us talk to those
individuals because we have value here at microsoft that they can actually use but you're not let me talk to
them so I basically take it upon myself to break down those walls improve to you that your java
developers can use this so as far as I'm concerned all code
is created equal I don't care what technology using to develop it nor do I care
what platform using to deploy it to we can help you here at microsoft
we have the tools we have the our we have work item tracking we have bug tracking we have
test case management what we mentioned this morning been able to compile objective
see natively unsigned a windows to target that's insane right that's the stuff we
never would have done before but we're trying to be where you are not everyone's
dot net developer right and we have to understand that and embrace that
and give you tools that you can use regardless if you're dot net developer not and that's what we've been trying to do here.
So, we talked a little bit about visual studio in
team foundation server team foundation server is not the next version of the ss.
Almost one make everyone in this room say that with me because that is like my biggest pet p when I go to customer site I
understand you need to get off the ss you might have outgrown it but this is not the next version of that
is a completely different tools yes it
has source control which is what the ss was but it also has all that other stuff I mentioned
automated build release management test case management bug tracking agile planning tools
the whole shooting match we have everything that you need from a software
companies perspective to...idea in turn into a working piece of software
...one vendor you don't have to go and buy one piece from one company one piece from another company
and hope that they actually talk to each other you could everything that you need no matter technology
or platform from one vendor if you don't want install yourself we also have...the cloud for
...well via so
...more and more functionality their and via so ironically enough
gets updated every three weeks every three weeks there's new features there and then we try to
bring those down every three months to what's on prime some companies are not comfortable with the
...so we still offer a on print version of everything I'm going to show you here today as well
How do we get you there again we're going to come to where you are if you're using dot net
...is fantastic visual studio I believe hands down as the best id on the
planet unbiased if years-old as I am you might
remember small computer company called compaq computers anyone old enough to remember that?
That's where I started and I started their writing windows applications
then if you remember that cplus-plus the good old days but we also have people...you're
inside the visual studio team explore experiences great if you're using a clips and I
mean...anywhere unix...linux...windows you can use team
explore everywhere because it runs on all those platforms it gives you that same rich experience at the
net developers have but in id that you're comfortable with which I'll be showing you today I've actually
developed an application that has a java front-end in a dot net...
or actually going to build them simultaneously we're going to deploy them simultaneously or even
a test them simultaneously using these tools and...effortless I've done this demo
three times this is the third-generation of this particular demo
it has never been easier I was actually shocked at how
fast I could put the pieces together to get this...work I just did this probably couple months ago
...ready twenty it was not this easy to do but I'll show you how we do it inside of
...now all java developer use eclipse some of...intelligent we're going to have
...and get you taken care of their as well because we have integration if you have some all legacy stuff
and our builder vsix cplus-plus six we...there's well wherever you are going to come
...meet you there release management can work with windows analytics we mention
...today in our keynote we
mentioned doctor in the past there's a lot of nice doctor integration and I'm going to show you how we can actually add those
task directly inside of really semantically actually have...support already.
If you're going to chef every familiar chef you might be doing a lot of development and
linux but they also support windows as well and we're going to be using shift today in this demo
...shown you how do you chef to be able to manager environment's but still layer that polish
...that's sugar on top of it that is release management they give you some of the things
...just doesn't give you out-of-the-box by itself an obviously desires...configuration or dsp
...I'm going to talk about that we're not actually using it in this demos I'm not going to labor that point
I have other decks where I go into more detail and you can actually look those up on channel nine so I'm where you
those right now so what are we trying to manage with release management what is the problem that we're trying to
solve what we're trying to solve is this problem all of this has to be
managed in organised when you want to do a proper deployment servers have to be
provision and configured that's for chef
...and things like...going to come and play and help you actually provision and
stand those machines up and then configure them because I need to make sure that machine has is running
on or my web apps is not going to work I need to make should has the right version the dot net framework on
...or my applications not want to work I don't want to
poor guy clicking and downloading installer...running through that because if I
...display scale out instead of another machine...to make sure
...schedule around that...ability to go click all the buttons and stand-up that machine and
because a human being is doing it there's a...is going to make a mistake just like the
...that cost them four hundred sixty million dollars
...linear poor guy who did it right seven out of eight...screwed up
...time the...screws up trying to configure one of our environment's how do once is that going to costas who's going
to know...actually automate that as much as we possibly can after we have the environment
...configured we now new installer application upon that machine but what's the
application is installed guess what...points at one place but qa
point somewhere else in production has to point yet somewhere else that's configuration
does not just easy enough just to copy the files across once the files are copy across
...need to be modified updated we...make sure that humans aren't doing that either how many
...developers do I have okay how many of you been burned by web dot
configure everyone raise your hands again right because if you don't raise your hand you're not an
...net developer we've all gone into a web
dot configured accidently fat fingered something left offer engl...bracket
...or quote forgot the closer quotes properly right and you get the yellow screen
...death I cannot parse this file any longer because a human being
went in there with the best intentions and just simply made a mistake and I'm going to show you
my favorite feature release management is the way they deal with web
...can fake so I will talk to-you about dominantly so we have to install the application that
the configure the application and then there's test.
I'm a huge fan of coded ui ...was talking about me going
to austin I'm doing one of my favorite talks in austin about coded ui basically take
...the weeds on that technology rewrite them from scratch all in csharp
it's just an awesome, awesome demo but not everyone likes coded
ui some people like selenium any selenium users in here I just started playing with that I have to
say very impressed very impressed with selenium geometry how we can actually use those
test directly inside of our pipeline right you don't have to do anything special we actually
know-how to run them and even store the results and published them with our releases as well right so again we're
...where you are after automated test run there's just some
tested just can't be automated right it's just either they're too expensive to automate they're very
what we call inconsistent sometimes...sometimes they don't it just it's easier to have a human being
run them so what we can do with release management because we have the ability to notify you
and wait for approvals we can actually deploy
your application run a battery of automated test for you and then pause.
...you go into that environment do what ever verifications that you need
whatever manual test that you need and then we'll pick back up what you say it's
...promoting that across for-you so we managed only
automated but also your manual testing and then finally we have a notifications in the approvals
this is huge even if I had gone inside of build...to copy the
files across for-you who said it was okay I guess the guy who triggered the build
...there's no other way for us to say someone else can go in there and stop it or posit but we actually give
me that ability right now so I really like the fact that I can do...configuration of my applications
in the...notifications and that's what we lay on top of any technology
your currently using today that simply moves bits...already have a battery of our show that knows how to do a lot
of cool automation for-you you-can continue to use that and simply add the notifications and approvals to
...using chef and you don't get those notifications and approvals we can add that
for you same thing with dockers same thing with puppet so just think of it as a
...that...going to put on the pipeline that you currently have today.
In the center of the world is something called and rm server is where
...configuration information is stored...all the decisions are made...the
environment's look like what you want to happen on each one of those environment's we store than what we call the server
essentially just a sequel server database with the web api on top of it right.
We can install this...prim or you can also have us hosted for you in what we call our
...are...management online so if you're using via so you already leverage
...they talk to each other right out-of-the-box it's
a really nice environment after we have the server configured what we have been
...endpoints to which we want to deploy if you look at the icon you can see I have a linux
icon and adrg icon in a windows icon you could put a w
...google doesn't matter what cloud you want to use we're going to be able to target any of those machines on prime or in the
klout.
Now you need a trigger a release and you can sugar...one of two ways you can either trigger
these manually or you can actually have continuous delivery continuous delivery is
the ability for someone to checking code that code then trigger a build
that building communicate with the release system saying I have bits that I needed to go deploy it'll start moving
into the pipeline literally no human intervention beyond checking encode
...this domino affect that will end up with your code running in production so that's what we mean
by continuous delivery we give you that right out-of-the-box as well and this analogy
here this slide...have a human being go into one of the user interfaces we used to
have a wpf client how many people are using the wpf client.
Or I'm sorry.
We're...that right now.
I'm not going to touch the...at all today so you're going to see what the new user interfaces it's really,
really nice so you're going to go to a client you can say I would like to release a build the service
...say okay great I'm...all of...different parts...need to be deployed
and orchestrate with the individual machines where those bits need to go regardless
of their windows or otherwise we can you chef doctored dac our shell microsoft
...agent whatever technology you need to get to those
machines will leverage it for-you in orchestrated and give you all the approve.
All right so what is dsp
I promise I'll talk to-you about it we're not actually using it in this demo but it's still something that
we're really excited about...want to make sure people are aware of I think the best way to describe
dac is to first describer world without which is the world that most of us live
in today most of us will assume the state of the machine to which we intend to
deploy are application...we assume that if it's a dot net application
that the net framework is install we assume if it's asp net application that is already
installed we make those assumptions and based on those assumptions
we then or run a series of actions upon that particular machine
...copy files across will go back in deploy or database
whatever the case might be and then afterwards we hope fingers crossed that
it's in the right environment however if any of our assumptions were wrong we get the
yellow screen a death...get a page cannot load or any...of different
errors that are applications going to throw because the assumptions were incorrect or maybe it
worked yesterday but someone went...to that machine and did something to it and now it doesn't
work today right we've all been there to where I don't understand it just worked last night
has anyone touch that machining have to go on this wild goose chase to find out who flipped what bit that
cause...applications...running desire
to configuration solves all those issues for-you instead of going on to machine and physically
...what you do instead is you describe what that
machine must look like you simply in text say it must have dot
net framework four-point-five it must have
is it must have this user in this group it must have this port on the
firewall open that are facts that must be true...give that information to the
...than takes that information...gets the current configuration of itself it
tested against the desired configuration that you just set me is should not
match it magically just makes it so it knows how to install those
bits it knows how to open up ports on your firewall it just doesn't the
...it can just do it is because of things called dc resources,
resources are small blobs of our shell
...the ability to do those three things get test
inset we have some for files so-if you want-to make sure that are file exist on a hard drive use something called
...file resource you want to make sure that a windows features
installed you something called a windows resource you kinda get the idea we have all
these different resources that we give you that you can use to describe what the machine must look like?
Now you can just imagine you might have scenarios where that resource doesn't exist yet
...guides like myself spend lots of time trying to figure out what you need
and we've created those resources one of them being a token...a shun resource
...I'm very proud of which is where the organization feature
...love so much from vone magically disappeared...we went to the
see and I wasn't willing to stand for that so I wrote my own token as a shun resource you
can now download that brings that feature back so you can start using in your
v next deployments right we actually ranger group just deploy that so it's officially
...a all...and all that nice stuff the final cool thing about dac is that
allows you to store your configuration as code.
As the configuration of your machine changes you can actually version that alongside the software and
which it supports every time I could produce a build and I deployed that
...actually...not only the code with
the configuration that supports that particular piece of code the...not only able to take the files
but also guarantee that I do have exactly what you said I'm supposed to have
...checks...a periodic bases that it still matches the last sent desired configuration
...go back and say hey it's been fifteen minutes I wonder if I still look like I'm supposed to
look if not I will make myself or if you want me to just scribble in the event log
on now no laundering compliance completely up to you so very powerful technology
and we can use this with release management very similar to desires
they configuration is chef?
That's why I said if we know chevy...know dac already because when you're building those recipes
those recipes are instructions that describe what you want your service to look like you combine those and
...execute those cookbooks on your nodes right dsp is a very similar technology so
you like one or the other you can use them both interchange we were going to be dealing with
the today cameras up because this screen I was talking about come up my...that
...have a given you guys for hours...free
...to like now training so the guys who just walked out of the room just left...for hours free
...so go ahead and just go along
into the website use that code go ahead and enjoy some of the content that they have available for you a
lot of good stuff all right enough talk time now for demo so this is the
point where I'm actually going to put the river to the road and we're going to try to see if we can get this stuff
to actually work all right so I kindly vaguely told you about the application so
what we've done here is we have an application that has a java front in written
...eclipse backed by a dot net...api
so it's a web api in written in csharp so we want to be able to do is be able to
track the work build the work in deployed the work all
is one project I don't want my java teens over in a lassie in bamboo
in jeans and all that stuff and my dot net team over and...fasten all this stuff I
want all the teams in one group because I'm still checking one project I wanna-be able to track as
in entity I want to be able to tested as an entity deploy it build the whole nine yards
...a very simple application let me just taken a quick tour this looks like I cheated because I know you got
the thing hold on man you said it was written in java but that is clearly.
The...vc template right because you go file new
nbc project that's exactly what it looks like dobie
suspicious that's exactly what I did and then I took the javascript and I took the csi
district over into a clips and...prove it to you right because I thought I should change it a
little bit more than I did but trust me it is another thing that I want to talk about what token
is a shun for a feature I was telling you about if we come to
the about page what I want to point out to you is this message right here
your application description page this is actually coming from the web api
the word itself now the way it's being displayed the fact that it's an age
...I believe instead of a new that's actually being controlled by the...team so as the product owner of
this project ives state that I want you guys to change the text and the
size which means I'm affecting both the java team and the net team
...to track that progress as a unit...tested so on so forth so right now
my goal is going to be able to do is to be able to change that but down below here...notice that
...an about url and a content url registry that up that's
known do.
These items here.
Do circle instead smpte?
I want to keep an eye on that value because this is my dev environment I also have a
qa environment and I'll show you that you're just a second sold those values are different because just imagine
a database connection by switch over to this guy these values.
Are different?
This one says qa so when I deploy the code...just copy the files out I
have to engl update where these urls point to make sure that my...points...the right
back in that's dot net my qa points at the right back in but you guys can replace this with the
...your database or what other configuration information that needs to change by environment I just
pick this for demonstration purposes but you understand the goal is I have values that need to be
manage in change per environment
...how we're able to do that as well so that's the application is pretty simple?
And, prove that it is inside of a clips in visual studio here is
my web api very simple as you can see it said that your application description
page number changing it to fabric...fiber twenty fourteen.
So, the detect is going to...what we want but we also want to description of a to change
or the representation of it and that comes from here I'm inside of a clips this is a
spring nbc applications so all
...based in all javabayes and I made the necessary changes to change it from a
...three I believe it was to a simple new inside of a
Also wanted to show you where I'm using those urls I just mention if I go to my home
controller here home controllers actually reading those values from here.
So, this is...actually going into what we call a properties file so I was not a java
developer I know enough java to get me this demo running right
I am a dot net developer so I know what a web dot configure was the equivalent of a web
dot configures a properties file from what I was able to find out in the java world it looks like
...I file has a value names in the values for that particular name value...I
can read those values inside of application so that I can do certain things with it like I would do with
a normal...as you can see down here.
This is what it looks like before I deploy it clearly those are
not the values you guys saw in the web application this value has to be over written at
deployed time to make sure points at the right location and I'll show you how we do that which
right so now I mention that we have continuous integration
continuous deployment so all I have to do here this is team explore by the way and I should be more specific
this is team explore everywhere because it is the plug-in that lives inside of a clips no matter where you are
...it gives me access to my work on tracking is the access to my documents reports
...source control everything I need to be productive on a daily basis
what is showing right now is that I have to pending changes files have been
...hard drive that I've yet to check in but need to go into the source control system trigger
...build and hopefully trigger release in a moment we'll be able to see that actual pages
been done all that's happening in the background articular tour of some of the other parts of the system
...this in while, you know, I'm down here the bottom
of actually associated a work item that says change text so
our product notice that I want you to change the...we actually created a work item for that and network item is going
to be associated to this particular build the always we'll go back and look at the
trace ability for some reason my network is moving very slowly so now I'm getting nervous.
Hopefully this is going to go off in save.
Hotel right.
This is taking on is supposed to...this isn't even part of my demo this is
...that leads into my...going to be along them...feeling solving this will savior just a
second...update there we go so now let's go ahead and see that's worth a round of applause rather...was able to
...freaking file.
Height let's go back here and start looking around what we're really interested in this should be triggering
off this particular build ed talked about this a little bit but what I wanted to point out
here's how easy it was for media be able to do a dot net build right alongside a
maven built...did this demo previously I think...europe so if you go
look at demo I do something very similar I had to go through so many gymnastics to
take microsoft build and get it to do both into play nice with release management and
to trigger the release afterwards if you look at what I had to write...like
...not worth it don't worry I shared that so if you are in that world I shared what I did
that was that hard to get to work the first-time...I came here and all I had to do so, you know,
what I need to do a maven build my click on these tab here next thing I know I have
access to maven and...I had access to darker and,...able I have access to everything that I needed
...what's really nice these are all open-source and expendable so there's something in this list that
you don't see don't feel that we can't do it just...yourself and I did the exact same thing I'm
using a technique called deployment slots if you go down here I'll show you will get to the release
I actually added my own resource or task...swap my slots for me because it wasn't in there are
...right so you can actually do whatever it is that you need to be done here let's go...if it actually triggered that
release forming through and go back here to...go back to queued and
...have something running perfect so this is the build running again?
They changed quite a bit so it's actually not only that run my build it
ran dot net unit test edit ran j unit testing
...my job application I didn't have to say what we're doing in java...so we...leverage your
ju test everything that I expected to happen when I...java or build dot net actually
happen simultaneously side-by-side it's already done it already dropped my output we
can go and take a closer look at some of the stuff that actually happens if I click on may even here will show me the log of
my maven build now you can see down here the bottom it actually ran three ju that
...as part of the build innovated failed my build
failed I also ransom dot net test as well and I can see that even better if article...
up and look at my actual build output so here are my test results.
The first link is to my dot net
...my second link is to my maven and I can go ahead and click on that for you and we
...effortlessly move between our build into our test
hub inferred test...our release hub to do this in the old stuff I would
have been inside of the fact client inside of rm I would've been a part of the web for service I would've
been a visual studio for the build part I...had to jumped three different
tools to be able to show you what I just showed you in one user interface or try to work really,
really hard to make sure that you have one pane of glass to which you can view all of your
...pipeline right from your builds to your check ends
to your releases to your test results everything you need to illegally
one-click away not start menu fire up microsoft test manager
...look at my results start menu fire police management let me go over there and approve my next
to my deployment we have everything that you need right here in front of you so these are maven
results I'm also going to show you later on in the demo selenium results coded
you why results I have unit test results from dot
net no matter how you want to tester application we have you supported that you can do it and
then visualize the results right here in front of,... need for-you
...start moving around like crazy so are build is already done...done we should have
...in-flight I can tell that we do basically by this color here so this is telling me
that this stage right now has a
release in-flight and I can see the release that's already inside of qa if I wanted to I can take a closer look
so let's just go ahead and see what's happening here...quicker closer look here so you can see I have
to of five tacit still need to be executed within our
...stage afterwards...go to our qa stage I had an automatic
approval of the very first entry into my...and I'll show you how I configured that that's
...didn't stop is also...exit the...states assuming that all my test actually
...it's going to do a selenium test of the user interface against
the chrome browser
...the job application actually was deployed success so again you might not be using
ieee you might be using comb or firefox or even if you using ie you're required to test own
comb and firefox as well we have the ability to do that not only with coded ui but
also with the selenium to set of tools as well a lot of...is going to be quick of all a lot of as even coming again these
all preview bits knowing actually play with this just yet but we're working on it if I
...go a little bit deeper you can actually see exactly what's going on here so what we have is an
automatic approval so shows me that is automatically approved I can download...that I need
...you can see right now we're basically poking a chef node but I mean by poking a chef node is that we
actually uploaded new values to a chef environment say hey look we took all
these files...them into as your blob storage now we want your linux
no to go nowhere in bob storage to go get the files from
...can copying down into tomcat so...way that we did that now...that real quickly is we use
...environment insider chef we use a task insider release management that
...updated the values from what we just use so that environment would know exactly what to go get
let's go back real quick look at how we added this thing here so far taking
to our chef task here I have a list of what we call attributes inside
the chef world and I can use macros inside of rm to be able expand them to values that
were just calculated as we process this particular
released because every time the drop location will be different the...number will be different we need a way to sharing that
information with those other systems we simply do that
via an environment inside a chef how many people are using chef already.
A couple you guys okay so I'll take you really quickly chef has a really nice interface feed
able to manage all of your assets in the past we made you do is you would add a
...a chef you have to come back in our in
add that same server again if I double work so what we wanted to do is allow you to
manage everything inside a chef your environment's your servers
...from the rem side able to target the environment so you don't have to add the service...
two different places right really reducing the amount of work it takes to manager chef environment on this particular
node here if you come in here mylar applications...people tracker
...updated these values one of them is where in where
what storage account in asher do I want you to use what prefix of the container do I want you to go
fine so you can go get the latest version of the files and I just copied up there for
you also have in their the about url
in the contact url those I can update from...or I can leave them static because for the environment they
really don't change but should they I have the our from rm to actually
drive a change in those particular values should for whatever reason they need to point somewhere else.
So, that's the...part if we go back I'll talk about some of the other pieces well.
This is actually running a battery of selenium test I
...call it a battery it's just one test but proves the point there is a selenium test that
fires up chrome goes to the dev version of my website in verify
that the text has been change to what it's supposed to be changed okay and...we're going to do that repeat
this inside of our qa environment we're going to a slightly differently because
in the qa environment I don't need to deploy the
website again the web api excuse me the web api inside of as using
...called deployment slots.
Who's familiar with...slots.
All right we have a awesome,
awesome feature called websites inside of measure automatically can
scale upper scale them down may have something called deployment slots so if I had application
a as a website I could say I would like there'd be another version of it
called a slot but I want to be able swap into production at a moment's notice it gives you
zero downtime deployments I can actually take my time and deploy
to that slot it all the files up...a quick test against and when I'm ready simply swap them
in at no one knows that I've done it because all we do in the back
...do a bip swab the virtual ip that was pointing at deb is now pointing at production and we
swap the other one around zero downtime deployment and that's what I'm utilizing here
and out-of-the-box this test did not exist but I knew what I wanted to do I simply wanted to
swap my slots if you come over here and you add a new task is going...the
bottom it looks like it's been there the entire time but I wrote that little piece of our
...and gave it to...instead I want this to be a tacit I can perform multiple times and
...really easy-to-use and now...could add as many as you want to we
have vtwo chef I really didn't like the way that the
chef tool worked so I wrote my own and I added into the system
...you can do this to extend...to be whatever it is that you needed to be
...to point out how easy it is to extend because it's a really,
really big plus the munch of rm in build for that matter is if
...can be done from our...it can be done from build if...can be done from our so it can be
done during your release it's that simple if you can show me a our
so command that does whatever it is that you want to do I can now plug-in...to your release I
...test run before after it I can ever...firing before and after it so
...already invested in our so you get tired of doing the
same task over and over again you don't have to...any of that away we can leverage all of that our
...part of release management anything you can do from our so you can do from rm so
...things I want-to talk to-you about as well as adding a new environment is a click of a button...it a name
...and prod here?
I also...control things, for example, like who the approvals...and if I went automatic on my
...looked exactly like this both the first to boxes
were checked on the key way slot however it did not I actually unchecked them
...put myself there as the approval so it's going to pause before actually goes into the
qa stage waiting for me to say yes everything looks okay so you can put yield...their...you feel that
...are necessary another thing that we realize there's information that needs
to be manage as far as what we call variables so this is were
able to store what I want to be assigned to this particular
environment such that when it runs this environment is able to take any variables here that I have
...use them to share with external systems as well...really nice
way of managing that little padlocked to the right allows me to encrypt this information as
well so if you need the...this down if this is a password that only a certain people should
know you don't have to worry about it just floating around in plain-text we can actually encrypt that information
and protective for use well this variable here pertains just to that one environment but
sometimes there's variables that apply to the entire release regardless of what environment is instead of having
...duplicated we actually give the ability here at
the higher-level to define that particular environment variable here I'm saying that I have a
...container I want to use across all my stages I don't have to repeat it when I
defined by variables so I
...it at a higher-level right and that storage key allows me to get into obviously my
...stewards as well we have things called artifacts if you're coming from the old
...world think of artifacts is components.
Ok, I'm already working on a blog post that maps the new...vernacular to the
old vernacular because we've changed almost every word right but I have a cheatsheet
...soon as I'm allowed to publish it will be one of the first blog post I publish so if you're familiar
with components that's what these guys are I'm saying I have one called people service and I have one
called people tracker these are the component some application and I'm going to need to deploy negative target those
two different environments our integration with chef unfortunate not many people...using
...yet is much tighter than it's ever been what I mean by that is not only do I get to tell
information actually create a actual linkage between my rm server
n my...server is not just arbitrary here's my username or password it's
a tight integration in linkage where they can actually communicate to each other...only can I manage
...this way I can actually wire jenkins this way...really understanding that people aren't going to use
are build system all the time...have investments in jenkins they already have investment and other systems
...you given you the ability to what we call service connections to be able to establish connections with
those other tools that you might want to be able to use obviously we have chef and asher but
you can also use things like jenkins I've seen the jenkins demos so I know that we have support for that as well and
more coming all the time the generic what is for any service...a username or password
in a url will be able to...that for you make a connection for...as well so let's go back and see how
far releases going and see if we can go and start doing some cool approvals here.
So, in this system.
I have my releases running so, those are my release.
And, I want to talk about the approval workflow to exciting the approval work roles really,
really nice in this particular version...my releases
in the past if I was in the fact client there was only one place I could go to approve
my releases if I got an email that I could go to the web client there's only one way for me to go in there
...my releases here I'm looking at a list of all my current releases our and...and that little
...let me know that there is an approval here waiting for me I don't even have to navigate
offer the screen to approve it and he's going to prove it right here but I might not...landed on this
particular page what if I was actually landed on the details of this particular guy or just so
happens that this guys here's well if I wanted to I can improve it from this particular screen but yet
and still there's yet another version that we could actually looking at we could be looking down here at the details of this particular item
in here years again so we're trying to make sure whatever it is that you need to do it's right there in front of
you all the time I don't want you navigating through some conti user interface to
get that one-page that allows me to do the tacit come here to do
ok so we're going-to we're going-to go ahead and that's verify that actually worked first before
you and I know that it worked the reason that I know that work because I have a selenium tested verify that
...worked had not worked we know because I have a...versus
the green checked in mary's you can see my application has been updated both parts of
my application the text got smaller which means the java side got updated the text changers means
the dot net saigon updated all happen automatically all at once but if we go over here
to my other stage nothing's happened yet the reason why is because
we're yielding our deployment better approval stops
...is...is donovan has to come in here and say it is okay for us to inner this
environment if he doesn't say so we're just going to sit here forever right so it's really nice to have those
gates I can slow it down if it needs to get that human intervention
...that interaction and let your...yet your process continue what we're going to
go back now they're going to actually say looks good in dev.
Let's go to queuing that's.
...go ahead and approve this at this point is
...kick-off again and start running this is a really good time for me to start taking questions so this is what I'm
going to do I'm going to actually pop-up something here this is actually my agent
running doesn't have to run as a consul it can actually run as a
services well but what should be happy now you can see is actually downloading artifact in a moment
...papa behind me but I'm going to be answering questions...won't be able to see that
...you guys into clapping for me because when that
ie window pops up I need you guys start happen so I know that is actually running dope.
...who ask questions do me a big favor find a microphone because they're recording this
...question they want to ask now we're waiting for this to run anyone, anyone
negative a job great perfectly real good you first do
those run soon-to-be run...in parallel.
That's a good question we can actually paralyze those...can actually do,
for example, in the...perspective you can actually run your build if you're doing both...simultaneously
...exact same time as well so yes we can paralyze that if you're really interested into the build stuff chris
patterson the pm for build is actually doing a talk I think it five or five-thirty it's going to
be a deep dive on build...doing more of the...inside he's doing more the build...
question you mentioned something about it not being released yet how much of this...use today.
None of it moi.
The question over here.
A very violent...
Took me...so they're going
to be integration with puppet as well as absolutely yes so there are talks
...republic what I want you guys to realize is if we don't make the integration doesn't mean
that doesn't exist you can make whatever integrations you want if there's an api that
can be exploited through a our shell that could be part of our tools that you
...simply add your own task there perfect question
...feature parity on your on print solution versus visual studio...
Feature parity.
Can you may example you think's going to be missing?
Orders wondering of all the features your
...for visual studio...also be available for...perfect now understand
...yes so what you're going to get on the boxy reinstall on print will match this,
yeah, okay, good...and more.
So, I noticed that you actually put.
You had to node addresses of the...qa can you give that...to
Yes, we innate dino what servers the
to be point-two each environment's sure we can actually put that information
...whoever actually needs it we can give permissions to either author them
their inside of our workflow or as I mentioned...wasn't talking
...we added customer inside we dog food this tool right so internally at microsoft we use
rm and whatever are internal users they had this existing cm
db...all their secrets...it...all...configuration
...the developers are actually driving they didn't want to move that inside of release management so
...able to do...the via our shell call out to their
...during their releasing grab all the secrets and configuration data
...release so wherever you want your data your developers destroyer and
...information will be able to go get it for yet runtime?
...shares...or python screech the...scriptas a
I that's a good one do me a favor ask that to chris
patterson if you can get to that five o'clock you'll know that answer for certain I know this
for...the agent itself does run on linux it runs on mac it runs on windows it's
...no js version of it that...other environment's so,
I know that supports note I don't know if...supporters other languages as good question.
So, we...automatic configuration food years ceo...inside
...management...plan to automatic provisioning I mean the
...having a devon qa platform which are not
...available to which would be provided...doings of...
walk who absolutely yes because we have things where we can actually integrate with as your
resource manager...
So, yes, so, we'll be able to define in a normal arm script little json I need these
environments and these machines and it will standing up for use part of our release absolutely and
...are that,...follow-up ahead question so someone had asked diesel available
that's a good question and I also have to ask that right because these are all internal
bits the team is working as fast as they can to try to get this ready for release so
I can't I don't know any dates I told them I'm going to deflecting...question you ask they actually didn't tell me
...either right so I honestly don't know when this is going to go a ga so
...can actually play with it I know they're working is...possibly can
...it fills believe it or not I struggled a little bit because I...with two different teams trying to get all
this stuff to work but it's working very consistently they're very close.
What if you're devin different environments are different domains that...great question and,
I'm going to answer now but I'm going to go even deeper and ignite so watch the video I do there so we have shadow accounts that
allow you across domains you can also have in this instance co-located
agents which is kinda cool so you can actually have an agent in the domain that you would your
servers not in so it doesn't have to across that domain bounding when it's actually trying to deploy those so you can
either you shadow accounts of that we've done historically shadow canvas basically exact same
username and password in one domain that is existent another and windows allow that
to authenticate across or you can do what we call co-located agents we actually take the
aged install in the domain that you needed...the server will be able to communicate with it?
The agent is...question was the agent as a server
it's a service rate this agent right here but also runs on linux...as well as just a...
js server is just an application ones there are there are we added questions
...about eight minutes left that's what I wanted to show you guys because that firing
up there this is awful lot easier when I did this before...had to install a test
comptroller iness test agent any microsoft test manager plan and
...decoded ui and then finally all this stuff to work to get that coded ui...I simply
had to say I want to run encoded ui test right and the agent took care of all the rest for me I wanted
...selenium test I just simply said I want to run a selenium test the agent took care
of everything for me the agent has something called demands on it so to be perfectly honest the
...I knew this agent I knew had all the capabilities that needed because you
get to describe what capabilities that has...you can the may
and that be true with your release or with your build it...find what...has all the domains to
can to basically satisfy your needs and I knew that this had visual studio installed
...all I needed versus the agent control and all the gymnastics...jump...in the past was so,
easy to get this courage...start running for me the question we're pretty heavily invested
...in the old version assert release management is the upgrade paths here's...
cast coming we haven't seen it yet but I've asked that specific question because I'm a huge
proponent of it I've been selling it like mad...they're going to kill me if there's not a nice way
they say we promise you there will be a upgrade path so that...be
taking care for you there is a doer evolve thingy I think if I move over to
Powerpoint thing.
So, I want to go over would we...the entire demo thankfully,
thankfully for me it actually worked and we're supposed to do now
is show you this little thing here...please,
please, please fill out these...I read every
single one of them there's a funny story about me when I was in europe ice got to speak at take
europe I spoke on wednesday and I...on friday I read a review that came from my
...they talk I stayed up all night thursday...twenty
...straight redoing my demo for friday so that I can make that guy happy I take
it that serious so please fill them out be honest
...be fair...if you like me the null invite me back and if not then I have no business
here anyway so just be honest but please, please take the time the fill them out I will literally read
every single one of them it's been a pleasure I hope this was helpful enjoy the rest to build.